He was the perfect weapon until he became the target.
The Bourne Identity is a action, drama, mystery film directed by Doug Liman.
Wounded to the brink of death and suffering from amnesia,
Jason Bourne is rescued at sea by a fisherman.
With nothing to go on but a Swiss bank account number, he starts to reconstruct
his life, but finds that many people he encounters want him dead.
However, Bourne realizes that he has the combat and mental skills
of a world-class spy—but who does he work for?
Jason Bourne, played by Matt Damon.
Marie Helena Kreutz, played by Franka Potente.
Alexander Conklin, played by Chris Cooper.
The Professor, played by Clive Owen.
Ward Abbott, played by Brian Cox.
Nykwana Wombosi, played by Adewale Akinnuoye-Agbaje.
The Bourne Identity is a 2002 American action-thriller film directed by Doug
Liman and written by Tony Gilroy and William Blake Herron.
Based on Robert Ludlum's 1980 novel of the same name, it is the first installment in the Bourne franchise, and the film
stars Matt Damon, Franka Potente, Chris Cooper, Clive Owen, Brian Cox, and Adewale Akinnuoye-Agbaje.
In the film, Jason Bourne (Damon) suffers from psychogenic amnesia and is forced to
fight to unlock his identity and his mysterious connection to the CIA.
Attempts to develop a feature film adaptation of Ludlum's novel first began in 1981 but
stalled after being passed to different distributors, with Warner Bros.
producing a television film adaptation in 1988.
Liman revived the feature film project in 1996 and worked with Ludlum and David Self on its screenplay after Gilroy initially
declined: Gilroy made several changes to the script upon joining, with additional contributions from Herron.
After Damon and Potente were cast, principal photography began in October 2000 and lasted until February
2001, with filming taking place in Paris, Prague, Imperia, Rome, Mykonos, and Zürich.
Production was troubled: the creators frequently clashed with studio executives
over delays, costs, last-minute changes, and unexpected reshoots.
Originally set for release in September 2001, it was theatrically released in
the United States on June 14, 2002, by Universal Pictures.
The film received positive reviews from critics, with praise for the direction, Damon's performance, action
sequences, and characters: it is considered one of the most influential action films of all time.
It grossed $214 million worldwide and was followed by the sequels The Bourne Supremacy (2004),
The Bourne Ultimatum (2007), The Bourne Legacy (2012) and Jason Bourne (2016).
The film explores themes of sniper, assassin, amnesia,
paris, france, based on novel or book.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.